<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multi-Tenant on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/multi-tenant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multi-Tenant on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:32:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/multi-tenant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multi Tenant Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/multi-tenant-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:32:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/multi-tenant-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working for a bank, we developed a highly successful platform for their retail users. It boasted modern features, robust security practices, and an exceptional user experience. However, we faced a new challenge when the bank requested us to extend the same platform for their High Net Worth Individual (HNI) users. They believed that since most of the features were similar, there was no need for two separate software systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class =&#34;image-container&#34; &gt;&#xA;&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/blogs/multi-tenant-architecture/multi-tenant-arch-before.png&#34; alt=&#34;Converting a single tenant architecture to a multitenant one&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%; border: 2px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 4px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-size: 14px; color: #666; margin-top: 8px;&#34;&gt;Fig 1: The existing architecture where another tenant is to be added&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;While the idea sounds exciting, and there are many common features in the platform, it is not as simple as it sounds.&#xA;The reports need a segregation for the governance purposes. The features were being used at peak on different times. Some rules and regulations were different in both the cases.&#xA;The onboarding flow for different types of users was different. The user experience for different tenants was different. All these complexities posed difficulties for us to simply reuse our microservices for multiple tenants.&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a solution architect, I took on the challenge of converting the existing single tenant architecture to a multi-tenant software architecture. To begin with, I carefully examined the similarities and differences between both systems. I then documented the potential risks and identified appropriate solutions and measures to address them effectively. And once done, we started making the changes step by step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
