<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Development on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Development on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 23:54:53 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Approaches to Software Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/architectural-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 23:54:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/architectural-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The architecture of a building plays a critical role in its usability and longevity. Similarly, the architecture of a software application is vital for ensuring scalability, maintainability, and overall system success.&#xA;In this blog, we will delve into different architectural approaches that can be employed to achieve these goals:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Layering&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Microservices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Event driven architecture&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Domain driven design&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;layering-defining-clear-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Layering: Defining Clear Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Layering is a fundamental architectural concept that involves segregating responsibilities into different layers. By creating distinct layers, we can clearly define the responsibilities of each layer, improving security and protecting downstream layers from potential attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application Security Verification Standard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/application-security-verification-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 10:11:38 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/application-security-verification-standard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;application-security-verification-standards&#34;&gt;Application Security Verification Standards&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensuring the security of an application is a complex task. To simplify this process, OWASP (Open Web Application Security Project) has developed &lt;cite&gt;a standardized approach&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/cite&gt; aimed at gauging and enhancing application security. Application Security Verification Standards a.k.a ASVS framework not only assists in evaluating the security posture of an application but also empowers development teams to build robust and secure software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consider a scenario where a fintech company is developing a new banking application. By incorporating OWASP&amp;rsquo;s recommendations into their development process, they can systematically identify and address security weaknesses, safeguard sensitive financial information and bolster customer trust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost of developing a software</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/cost-of-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/cost-of-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;trigger-for-this-blog&#34;&gt;Trigger for this blog&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was pair programming during an interview, where the candidate had shared his screen and I was working side by side with him, trying to understand the solution he was presenting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: his computer screen flashed a message about his Windows license being expired. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but ask, and what I heard surprised me. He proudly admitted to using a &amp;ldquo;not-so-legal&amp;rdquo; version of Windows because he wanted to stick it to Microsoft for their high prices, especially when there&amp;rsquo;s a free alternative like Ubuntu available.&#xA;I did not take a screenshot, but it looked something like this&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/blogs/cost-of-software/windows.png&#34; alt=&#34;windows license message&#34; class=&#34;responsive-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Stories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/anecdotes/anecdote1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/anecdotes/anecdote1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;once-upon-a-time&#34;&gt;Once Upon a time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;in Sriganganagar, a legend was born&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Hosted Captcha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/solutions/self-hosted-captcha/self-hosted-captcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/solutions/self-hosted-captcha/self-hosted-captcha/</guid>
      <description>Design and implement a secure, self-hosted CAPTCHA service. Learn about features, accessibility, integration, and architecture for protecting applications from bots while ensuring a seamless user experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Tech Ecosystem - A Techie&#39;s Take on Software Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/technologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a technology enthusiast, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the honor of witnessing the ever-evolving landscape of software development. In today&amp;rsquo;s world, software is the beating heart of virtually every industry. It&amp;rsquo;s what empowers businesses to connect with their audience, streamline operations, and explore new horizons. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to dive into the core pillars of our technology stack, giving special attention to the web, mobile, services, and DevOps domains. Let&amp;rsquo;s journey through these technologies and explore how they&amp;rsquo;re shaping the present and future of software development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
