<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 09:29:59 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Financial Advice Generator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2025/jul/personalized-financial-advice-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 09:29:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2025/jul/personalized-financial-advice-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving FinTech industry, customers expect tailored financial guidance that aligns with their unique goals, spending habits, and risk profiles. Traditional one-size-fits-all advisory models often fall short in delivering meaningful value, especially for digitally savvy users who demand personalization similar to what they experience in e-commerce or media platforms. A Personalized Financial Advice Generator addresses this gap by leveraging AI to analyze individual transaction patterns, lifestyle choices, and financial aspirations, delivering real-time, hyper-personalized insights that empower users to make smarter financial decisions and deepen their trust in the FinTech platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pins and Passwords</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2025/jul/pins-and-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 09:11:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2025/jul/pins-and-passwords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How many of us have stared blankly at a login screen, desperately trying to recall that complex password? It’s a frustratingly common experience, and a surprisingly significant hurdle in securing mobile applications. During my architecture design consulting sessions, I come across this situation multiple times – and I love to build authentication systems that don’t sacrifice user experience for security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My journey into this space began over a decade ago, designing and implementing software solutions for some of the largest banks across the globe. During that time, I witnessed firsthand the critical balance between robust security measures and the ease with which users can interact with their financial data. I realized that overly complicated authentication processes often lead to user frustration, abandonment, and ultimately, a weakened security posture – users are more likely to opt for simpler, less secure methods to avoid the hassle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Channel Banking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/solutions/channel-banking-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 09:58:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/solutions/channel-banking-project/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive documentation for a Channel Banking application covering SDLC processes, mobile and web apps, APIs, admin tools, and reporting. Supports retail and business banking use cases with detailed project, architecture, and development insights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Test Data Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2025/jan/the-test-data-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 21:48:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2025/jan/the-test-data-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-test-data-dilemma-a-silent-challenge-in-software-development&#34;&gt;The Test Data Dilemma: A Silent Challenge in Software Development&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When building software, one big challenge often goes unnoticed – getting the right test data. As a software architect, I have worked with many customers to create software systems. A common issue I’ve faced is that customers don’t have enough good test data for developers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just a small problem. It can lead to serious issues, including legal trouble. Let’s talk about this problem, why it happens, and how we can fix it in a simple and effective way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Self-Hosted Captcha Service: Challenges, Insights, and Solutions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/nov/designing-a-captcha-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 10:31:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/nov/designing-a-captcha-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: What if the familiar captcha boxes we encounter daily were designed by your team, tailored specifically to your organization’s needs?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Recently, I took on the challenge of creating a custom, self-hosted captcha service for a client. It sounded simple at first—why reinvent the wheel when solutions like Google’s reCAPTCHA already exist? But there was a twist: the client wanted full control, aiming to ensure data privacy and integrate accessibility features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Journey with Finacle: Lessons Learned in Banking Software Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/aug/my-learnings-from-finacle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 09:31:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/aug/my-learnings-from-finacle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I consider myself fortunate to have been hired by Infosys right after college, and even luckier to work on a world-class banking product – Finacle. When I joined, Infosys was revamping the channel layer of Finacle, and I was given the incredible opportunity to contribute to this effort from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;key-learnings-from-developing-finacle-e-banking-architecture-feba&#34;&gt;Key Learnings from Developing Finacle E-Banking Architecture (FEBA)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Working on the Finacle E-Banking Architecture (FEBA) taught me many invaluable lessons. Here are the key takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authenticating Services in a Microservices Environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/jul/authenticating-services-in-a-microservices-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 14:31:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/jul/authenticating-services-in-a-microservices-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is easier to edit a draft than to create a new. I   understand that this blog is not upto the mark that I want it to be, however, I am still publishing it, so that I can keep on improving it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The code for this blog is checked-in at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mohitkanwar/spring-microservices-framework&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mohitkanwar/spring-microservices-framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While developing a microservices setup, one of the prime aspect is taking care of the security of the APIs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Based Otp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/jul/time-based-otp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/jul/time-based-otp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While using any corporate application that is secured by Two Factor Authentication (TFA), we get an option to scan a QR code via an authenticator app. And then after, the number generated by the authenticator app works in login with the given service. Interesting thing is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even need internet or any active connection between the authenticator and the server for the authentication to take place.&#xA;Have you ever wondered how the two factor authenticators e.g. Google Authenticator or Microsoft Authenticator work?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering Skills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/jul/software-engineering-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:01:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/jul/software-engineering-skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of my friends come to me and ask about the skills required to grow in the software engineering field. The primary intention behind their questions is usually to understand which latest technologies they need to learn. Should they focus on improving their Python or Java skills? Should they focus on Frontend, Backend or DevOps?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While learning specific technologies or languages is certainly important, I believe that it constitutes only a small portion of what it takes to become a good software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apis Are Forever</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/may/apis-are-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 11:45:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/may/apis-are-forever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;apis-like-diamonds-are-forever&#34;&gt;APIs, like diamonds are forever.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;APIs are expensive to build and maintain, and once developed they have little resale value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an architect, we have to give full attention to the APIs being developed. In one of the assignment, I observed four to five versions of the same API all running parallally, because there is no single version that caters to all the requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The existing spagatti code doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow it to be fixed within the given time frame, and the default accepted way of working has become to add a new version of the API whenever a slight change is required in the API.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Components in Llm Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/may/components-in-llm-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 09:28:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/may/components-in-llm-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;transformer-model&#34;&gt;Transformer Model&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever gotten frustrated with chatbots that just don&amp;rsquo;t seem to understand the full flow of conversation? Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed machine translations that miss the mark completely. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s a reason for that –  until recently, computers had a tough time understanding the deeper connections between words in a sentence. But a game-changer called the Transformer model is here!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Transformer model is a deep learning architecture introduced in the paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.03762&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Attention is All You Need&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. It revolutionized the field of natural language processing (NLP) by introducing a novel mechanism based on attention rather than recurrent or convolutional layers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence Applications in Fintech</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/apr/artificial-intelligence-applications-in-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 17:12:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/apr/artificial-intelligence-applications-in-fintech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence stands out as a powerful and versatile technology that holds the potential to revolutionize various industries. Among these industries, FinTech emerges as a domain where AI can truly shine and deliver impactful results. The intersection of finance and technology presents a fertile ground for AI applications to streamline processes, enhance customer experiences, and drive innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the FinTech industry, AI is being harnessed to tackle complex challenges and unlock new opportunities. From fraud detection and risk management to personalized financial advice and automated trading, AI is reshaping the way financial services are delivered and consumed. The ability of AI algorithms to analyze vast amounts of data, identify patterns, and make data-driven decisions in real-time is transforming how financial institutions operate and interact with customers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Models in Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/apr/models-in-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 10:22:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/apr/models-in-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt; is a simplified version of a real world entity that focuses on some of the properties of the real object that are under study. Similar to the models doing a ramp walk, help us understand how the clothes developed by a designer might look, models are an integral part of software industry, that help in catering to a specific set of properties that we want to create in the soft world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/apr/retrieval-augmented-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 17:14:04 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/apr/retrieval-augmented-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-rag&#34;&gt;Introduction to RAG&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) is a cutting-edge technique in artificial intelligence that merges generative AI capabilities with large language models to enhance language generation tasks. By integrating both parametric memory (learned patterns) and non-parametric memory (external knowledge sources), RAG models aim to boost the specificity, diversity, and accuracy of the text they generate to new heights. Unlike traditional Large Language Models (LLMs) that rely solely on internal data, RAG allows for seamless access to external knowledge repositories like Wikipedia. This access enables RAG models to deepen their understanding of context and improve the overall quality of the text they produce.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequence Diagrams using Mermaid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/apr/sequence-diag-mermaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 19:35:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/apr/sequence-diag-mermaid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been creating designs for software solutions for quite some time now. A picture is worth a thousand words and hence the different diagrams really help in expressing the software designs in a better way to fellow team mates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Sequence diagram is a powerful tool that shows the step-by-step interactions between different parts of a software system, making it easier to understand how messages and actions flow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve utilized various tools like Visio and Draw.io for manual diagram creation. However, in recent times, I&amp;rsquo;ve found mermaid.js to be my preferred tool for crafting sequence diagrams. Mermaid.js stands out as it enables diagram creation using a specific DSL, primarily in markdown format. This markdown is swiftly transformed into shareable diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Reconciliation Patterns in an Event driven AWS Ecosystem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/data-recon-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 18:23:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/data-recon-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently attended an XKE (Xebia&amp;rsquo;s Knowledge Exchange) session delivered by Mr. Chandan Kumar and Mr. Himanshu Jain.&#xA;In this session they talked about the Data Reconciliation Patterns in an Event driven AWS Ecosystem, and I am presenting here my learnings from the session.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data reconciliation is vital to ensure that data across different systems or components remains consistent and in sync. In the realm of application development, multiple systems work together to deliver specific functionalities. However, due to the complexity involved, system failures mid-transaction can lead to data inconsistencies. As vigilant system architects, it is crucial to design robust systems capable of recovering from such data irregularities. Data reconciliation plays a key role in rectifying data inconsistencies, automating error resolutions, and allowing for manual interventions when needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approaches to Software Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/architectural-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 23:54:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/architectural-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The architecture of a building plays a critical role in its usability and longevity. Similarly, the architecture of a software application is vital for ensuring scalability, maintainability, and overall system success.&#xA;In this blog, we will delve into different architectural approaches that can be employed to achieve these goals:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Layering&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Microservices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Event driven architecture&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Domain driven design&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;layering-defining-clear-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Layering: Defining Clear Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Layering is a fundamental architectural concept that involves segregating responsibilities into different layers. By creating distinct layers, we can clearly define the responsibilities of each layer, improving security and protecting downstream layers from potential attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Management Microservice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/configuration-management-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:34:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/configuration-management-microservices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Configuration management is a crucial yet often overlooked aspect of working with microservices. In a microservices environment, managing various configurations, including those related to client applications, business processes, and technical settings, can become complex. This complexity is further amplified when dealing with multiple environments such as development, QA, and production, each requiring different configurations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While organizations typically maintain version control for their codebase, the versioning of configurations is sometimes neglected. In this article, we will explore how we can create a configuration management microservice using Spring Cloud Config, a powerful solution provided by the Spring framework. We will specifically focus on its applicability in the FinTech industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application Security Verification Standard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/application-security-verification-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 10:11:38 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/mar/application-security-verification-standard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;application-security-verification-standards&#34;&gt;Application Security Verification Standards&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensuring the security of an application is a complex task. To simplify this process, OWASP (Open Web Application Security Project) has developed &lt;cite&gt;a standardized approach&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/cite&gt; aimed at gauging and enhancing application security. Application Security Verification Standards a.k.a ASVS framework not only assists in evaluating the security posture of an application but also empowers development teams to build robust and secure software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consider a scenario where a fintech company is developing a new banking application. By incorporating OWASP&amp;rsquo;s recommendations into their development process, they can systematically identify and address security weaknesses, safeguard sensitive financial information and bolster customer trust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Authentication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/feb/adaptive-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 16:25:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/feb/adaptive-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;motivation-behind-this-blog&#34;&gt;Motivation behind this blog&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During a visit to my friend&amp;rsquo;s house, I needed to check my email on his laptop. Upon entering my credentials, I encountered a captcha prompt unexpectedly. After successfully navigating through the captcha challenge, I was then required to enter an additional layer of OTP. It was only after overcoming both obstacles that I finally gained access to my emails.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, I rarely need to input my credentials on my iPad or phone to access Gmail. After logging in once, I can consistently access my emails without the need to reauthenticate my identity each time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broken Access Control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/feb/broken-access-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 17:37:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/feb/broken-access-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;access-control-in-owasp-top-10&#34;&gt;Access Control in OWASP top 10&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Access control is a crucial aspect of application security that ensures users can only perform actions within their authorized permissions. However, broken access control vulnerabilities can lead to unauthorized access, data breaches, and other security risks. In this blog, I want to talk about a very common observation that I have while reviewing codes. Well, not only observed by me, broken access control is the number one in &lt;a href=&#34;https://owasp.org/Top10/A01_2021-Broken_Access_Control/&#34;&gt;OWASP Top 10 2021 list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sim Binding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/sim-binding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 13:08:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/sim-binding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;sim-binding&#34;&gt;Sim Binding&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sim binding is a process requirement by RBI to provide secure mobile applications. The RBI has issued the Master Direction on Digital Payment Security Controls to ensure the security of digital payment systems. The directions apply to scheduled commercial banks, small finance banks, payments banks, and credit card issuing NBFCs. The guidelines emphasize the need for a robust governance structure and implementation of security controls for digital payment products and services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dev Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/dev-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 09:16:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/dev-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.blog/2024-01-24-how-githubs-developer-experience-team-improved-innerloop-development/&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on the GitHub blog that discusses how GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Developer Experience (DX) team improved innerloop development.&#xA;While reading the article I was reminded of this quote&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clients do not come first. Employees come first. If you take care of your employees, they will take care of the clients.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;— &lt;cite&gt;Richard Branson&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And as a leader of a development team, I was made to think what am I doing for better experience of my developers, and what can be done better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi Tenant Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/multi-tenant-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:32:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/multi-tenant-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working for a bank, we developed a highly successful platform for their retail users. It boasted modern features, robust security practices, and an exceptional user experience. However, we faced a new challenge when the bank requested us to extend the same platform for their High Net Worth Individual (HNI) users. They believed that since most of the features were similar, there was no need for two separate software systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class =&#34;image-container&#34; &gt;&#xA;&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/blogs/multi-tenant-architecture/multi-tenant-arch-before.png&#34; alt=&#34;Converting a single tenant architecture to a multitenant one&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%; border: 2px solid #ddd; border-radius: 4px; box-shadow: 0 2px 4px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-size: 14px; color: #666; margin-top: 8px;&#34;&gt;Fig 1: The existing architecture where another tenant is to be added&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;While the idea sounds exciting, and there are many common features in the platform, it is not as simple as it sounds.&#xA;The reports need a segregation for the governance purposes. The features were being used at peak on different times. Some rules and regulations were different in both the cases.&#xA;The onboarding flow for different types of users was different. The user experience for different tenants was different. All these complexities posed difficulties for us to simply reuse our microservices for multiple tenants.&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a solution architect, I took on the challenge of converting the existing single tenant architecture to a multi-tenant software architecture. To begin with, I carefully examined the similarities and differences between both systems. I then documented the potential risks and identified appropriate solutions and measures to address them effectively. And once done, we started making the changes step by step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kareena Kapoor Controllers and the Fluffy Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/kareena-kapoor-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/kareena-kapoor-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A microservice is a small, independent application that is designed to perform a specific business functionality. It is a software architectural style that structures an application as a collection of loosely coupled services, each running in its own process and communicating with each other through lightweight mechanisms, such as HTTP or messaging protocols.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, we are going to learn how to structure an individual microservice application, and break it down into different components. We are going to use SpringBoot as a tool to design the microservice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost of developing a software</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/cost-of-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/cost-of-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;trigger-for-this-blog&#34;&gt;Trigger for this blog&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was pair programming during an interview, where the candidate had shared his screen and I was working side by side with him, trying to understand the solution he was presenting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: his computer screen flashed a message about his Windows license being expired. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but ask, and what I heard surprised me. He proudly admitted to using a &amp;ldquo;not-so-legal&amp;rdquo; version of Windows because he wanted to stick it to Microsoft for their high prices, especially when there&amp;rsquo;s a free alternative like Ubuntu available.&#xA;I did not take a screenshot, but it looked something like this&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/blogs/cost-of-software/windows.png&#34; alt=&#34;windows license message&#34; class=&#34;responsive-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Stories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/anecdotes/anecdote1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/anecdotes/anecdote1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;once-upon-a-time&#34;&gt;Once Upon a time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;in Sriganganagar, a legend was born&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Hosted Captcha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/solutions/self-hosted-captcha/self-hosted-captcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/solutions/self-hosted-captcha/self-hosted-captcha/</guid>
      <description>Design and implement a secure, self-hosted CAPTCHA service. Learn about features, accessibility, integration, and architecture for protecting applications from bots while ensuring a seamless user experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamification - Make it interesting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/gamification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/gamification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-by-gamification&#34;&gt;Learning by Gamification&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have ever taught a child who is just starting school, you may have noticed that concepts that seem simple to you can be quite complex for them. This is due to their limited understanding and lack of prior knowledge. Additionally, children often have short attention spans and can easily be distracted by their surroundings, making it even more challenging to teach them new concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to better understand how to teach these concepts effectively, I reached out to a school teacher named Mrs. Rasika. She graciously invited me to observe one of her classes, and the experience made me nostalgic for my own school days. During this day, I witnessed Mrs. Rasika using creative and engaging methods to teach different subjects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GIFT City- India&#39;s Gateway to Global Business Excellence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/gift-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/gift-city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Situated between Ahmedabad and Gandhinagar, along the Sabarmati river, GIFT City (Gujarat International Finance Tec-City) emerges as India&amp;rsquo;s beacon of global business excellence. The city&amp;rsquo;s futuristic infrastructure, coupled with its strategic location, sets the stage for a transformative business environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;map-container&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d58688.8183877461!2d72.63974276055461!3d23.16833320432678!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x395e8019d43730db%3A0x7044e9a2cb290ed!2sGujarat%20International%20Finance%20Tec-City%2C%20Gujarat%20382355!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sin!4v1703757182932!5m2!1sen!2sin&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34;  style=&#34;border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;no-referrer-when-downgrade&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;Within the boundaries of GIFT City, banks are pioneering the concept of IFSC Banking Units (IBUs). These units, akin to offshore branches within the IFSC zone, play a pivotal role in shaping India&#39;s global financial connectivity.&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;empowering-global-business&#34;&gt;Empowering Global Business&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-foreign-companies&#34;&gt;For Foreign Companies:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;access-to-indian-rupee-market&#34;&gt;Access to Indian Rupee Market&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IFSC Banking Units (IBUs) in GIFT City make it simpler for businesses to use Indian rupees. Normally, dealing with Indian money involves lots of rules and complicated steps. But with IBUs, companies can work with Indian rupees without facing those complicated rules.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the logging architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/logging-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/logging-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In any software development project, logging plays a vital role in understanding and troubleshooting the behavior of applications. Imagine you are working on a web application that consists of multiple components, such as a frontend server, backend server, and a database. Each of these components generates logs that provide valuable insights into their operations. For example, the frontend server logs can reveal user interactions, while the backend server logs can show the processing of requests and responses. These logs act as a valuable source of information for developers and support teams to diagnose issues, track performance, and monitor the overall health of the system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art and Science of Prompt Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/prompt-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/prompt-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;content&#xA;With the rise of conversational and generative AI systems like ChatGPT, Bard etc., the way of working is being disrupted. To not be afraid of AI snatching jobs, we must embrace AI and adpot it in our ways of working to deliver better and faster.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use AI as an assistant and getting work done by it, we need to be able to communicate our needs to it. When we ask the AI to do something for us, the requests are known as prompts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Global Diversity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/working-with-global-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/working-with-global-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;embracing-global-diversity-insights-from-a-world-of-experiences&#34;&gt;Embracing Global Diversity: Insights from a World of Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the onset of my career, the allure of working &amp;ldquo;On-Site&amp;rdquo; was a shared aspiration among my peers and me. The prospect of immersing ourselves in diverse cultures, collaborating closely with customers, and gaining insights into varied business operations was enticing. On-site assignments promised not just professional growth but also a glimpse into a world previously beyond our reach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, transitioning from core product development to customer-facing roles was a hurdle. Yet, the door to global experiences swung open when I joined Xebia as a trainer. Suddenly, I found myself traversing continents, training teams in countries spanning Netherlands, Mauritius, Bahrain, Qatar, the Philippines, Thailand, and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Passwordless Authentication with FIDO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/fido/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/fido/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometime back, I created &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/mohit-kanwar-7668a211_passwordless-authentication-activity-6926093155184320512-Nnhu?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; on linked-in on explainig how passwords are not a good fit for authentication. In continuation to that, I would like to talk about FIDO Alliance.&#xA;In the ever-evolving landscape of cybersecurity, the traditional method of password-based authentication has long been at the forefront of both convenience and vulnerability.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Enter FIDO, an innovative and transformative technology that revolutionizes the way we verify identity and secure access to digital systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Art and Essentials of API Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/crafting-api-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/crafting-api-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unveiling-the-elegance-of-api-design&#34;&gt;Unveiling the Elegance of API Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the intricate world of software architecture, API design emerges as a symphony, a composition that can either elevate a system to greatness or introduce complexities that echo through time. Joshua Bloch&amp;rsquo;s insights, shared in the iconic talk &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aAb7hSCtvGw&amp;amp;t=8s&#34;&gt;How to Design a Good API and Why it Matters&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rsquo; in the year 2007, still serves as guiding principles for architects and developers seeking to sculpt APIs that stand the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The technology of modern banks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/the-technology-of-modern-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/the-technology-of-modern-banks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-technology-of-modern-banks-innovations-shaping-the-financial-landscape&#34;&gt;The Technology of Modern Banks: Innovations Shaping the Financial Landscape&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The banking industry, a traditionally conservative sector, has witnessed a radical transformation driven by technological advancements. In the digital age, modern banks have become more than just places to store money; they are dynamic hubs of financial innovation. In this article, we delve deep into the technologies that are reshaping the modern banking landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-digital-banking-revolution&#34;&gt;The Digital Banking Revolution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-banking-where-convenience-meets-innovation&#34;&gt;Online Banking: Where Convenience Meets Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The evolution of the internet has given rise to modern online banking, enabling customers to access their accounts through web and mobile applications. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. Modern online banking has expanded to include the convenience of making transactions via wearables, such as smartwatches and glasses. Moreover, advances in language engineering have resulted in the development of home speakers like Alexa, allowing customers to interact with conversational bots to make payments. It&amp;rsquo;s now as simple as saying, &amp;ldquo;Alexa, pay my rent,&amp;rdquo; and the rent is paid, making banking a seamless part of daily life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of Large Language Models in the World of IT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/large-language-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/large-language-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;unlocking-the-power-of-large-language-models-in-the-world-of-it-embracing-chatgpt&#34;&gt;Unlocking the Power of Large Language Models in the World of IT: Embracing ChatGPT&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As technology continues to evolve, the integration of artificial intelligence has become a game-changer in both the software and banking industries. One remarkable development in this AI landscape is the advent of Large Language Models (LLMs), which are transforming the way we interact with computers and data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-large-language-models&#34;&gt;Introduction to Large Language Models&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Large Language Model, or LLM, is more than just a fancy acronym. It represents a type of artificial intelligence algorithm, often referred to as a &amp;ldquo;model,&amp;rdquo; that undergoes extensive training on an expansive corpus of textual data. This training equips LLMs with a profound understanding of language patterns and structures, enabling them to perform a wide array of tasks, including:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Tech Ecosystem - A Techie&#39;s Take on Software Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/technologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a technology enthusiast, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the honor of witnessing the ever-evolving landscape of software development. In today&amp;rsquo;s world, software is the beating heart of virtually every industry. It&amp;rsquo;s what empowers businesses to connect with their audience, streamline operations, and explore new horizons. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to dive into the core pillars of our technology stack, giving special attention to the web, mobile, services, and DevOps domains. Let&amp;rsquo;s journey through these technologies and explore how they&amp;rsquo;re shaping the present and future of software development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Gallery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 18:35:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
