<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technologies on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/technologies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technologies on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/technologies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The technology of modern banks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/the-technology-of-modern-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/the-technology-of-modern-banks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-technology-of-modern-banks-innovations-shaping-the-financial-landscape&#34;&gt;The Technology of Modern Banks: Innovations Shaping the Financial Landscape&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The banking industry, a traditionally conservative sector, has witnessed a radical transformation driven by technological advancements. In the digital age, modern banks have become more than just places to store money; they are dynamic hubs of financial innovation. In this article, we delve deep into the technologies that are reshaping the modern banking landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-digital-banking-revolution&#34;&gt;The Digital Banking Revolution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-banking-where-convenience-meets-innovation&#34;&gt;Online Banking: Where Convenience Meets Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The evolution of the internet has given rise to modern online banking, enabling customers to access their accounts through web and mobile applications. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. Modern online banking has expanded to include the convenience of making transactions via wearables, such as smartwatches and glasses. Moreover, advances in language engineering have resulted in the development of home speakers like Alexa, allowing customers to interact with conversational bots to make payments. It&amp;rsquo;s now as simple as saying, &amp;ldquo;Alexa, pay my rent,&amp;rdquo; and the rent is paid, making banking a seamless part of daily life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Tech Ecosystem - A Techie&#39;s Take on Software Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/technologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a technology enthusiast, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the honor of witnessing the ever-evolving landscape of software development. In today&amp;rsquo;s world, software is the beating heart of virtually every industry. It&amp;rsquo;s what empowers businesses to connect with their audience, streamline operations, and explore new horizons. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to dive into the core pillars of our technology stack, giving special attention to the web, mobile, services, and DevOps domains. Let&amp;rsquo;s journey through these technologies and explore how they&amp;rsquo;re shaping the present and future of software development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
