<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:40:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time Based Otp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/jul/time-based-otp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/2024/jul/time-based-otp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While using any corporate application that is secured by Two Factor Authentication (TFA), we get an option to scan a QR code via an authenticator app. And then after, the number generated by the authenticator app works in login with the given service. Interesting thing is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even need internet or any active connection between the authenticator and the server for the authentication to take place.&#xA;Have you ever wondered how the two factor authenticators e.g. Google Authenticator or Microsoft Authenticator work?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sim Binding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/sim-binding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 13:08:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/sim-binding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;sim-binding&#34;&gt;Sim Binding&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sim binding is a process requirement by RBI to provide secure mobile applications. The RBI has issued the Master Direction on Digital Payment Security Controls to ensure the security of digital payment systems. The directions apply to scheduled commercial banks, small finance banks, payments banks, and credit card issuing NBFCs. The guidelines emphasize the need for a robust governance structure and implementation of security controls for digital payment products and services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
