<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FinTech on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fintech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FinTech on Mohit Kanwar&#39;s App : My Cents</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fintech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The technology of modern banks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/the-technology-of-modern-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/the-technology-of-modern-banks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-technology-of-modern-banks-innovations-shaping-the-financial-landscape&#34;&gt;The Technology of Modern Banks: Innovations Shaping the Financial Landscape&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The banking industry, a traditionally conservative sector, has witnessed a radical transformation driven by technological advancements. In the digital age, modern banks have become more than just places to store money; they are dynamic hubs of financial innovation. In this article, we delve deep into the technologies that are reshaping the modern banking landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-digital-banking-revolution&#34;&gt;The Digital Banking Revolution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-banking-where-convenience-meets-innovation&#34;&gt;Online Banking: Where Convenience Meets Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The evolution of the internet has given rise to modern online banking, enabling customers to access their accounts through web and mobile applications. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. Modern online banking has expanded to include the convenience of making transactions via wearables, such as smartwatches and glasses. Moreover, advances in language engineering have resulted in the development of home speakers like Alexa, allowing customers to interact with conversational bots to make payments. It&amp;rsquo;s now as simple as saying, &amp;ldquo;Alexa, pay my rent,&amp;rdquo; and the rent is paid, making banking a seamless part of daily life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of Large Language Models in the World of IT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/large-language-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/large-language-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;unlocking-the-power-of-large-language-models-in-the-world-of-it-embracing-chatgpt&#34;&gt;Unlocking the Power of Large Language Models in the World of IT: Embracing ChatGPT&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As technology continues to evolve, the integration of artificial intelligence has become a game-changer in both the software and banking industries. One remarkable development in this AI landscape is the advent of Large Language Models (LLMs), which are transforming the way we interact with computers and data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-large-language-models&#34;&gt;Introduction to Large Language Models&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Large Language Model, or LLM, is more than just a fancy acronym. It represents a type of artificial intelligence algorithm, often referred to as a &amp;ldquo;model,&amp;rdquo; that undergoes extensive training on an expansive corpus of textual data. This training equips LLMs with a profound understanding of language patterns and structures, enabling them to perform a wide array of tasks, including:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
